A Guide to the Ezra A. Frantz Papers, 1906-1960
Frantz, Ezra A., papers
1906-1960
Frantz, Ezra A.
71-176; 92-041
2 ft., 2 in.
Dolph Briscoe Center for American History, The University of Texas at Austin
The Ezra A. Frantz Papers, 1906-1960, consist of the business records of the Frantz Buckle Company in Weatherford, Texas, as well as personal records of Frantz and his social activities.
Biographical Note
Ezra Allen Frantz (1875-1964) was born to Michael and Barbara Brubaker Frantz in Pleasant Hill, Illinois. In 1896, he married Mary Lavanna Buckley, with whom he had five children, including historian Joe B. Frantz. After dissolving his manufacturing partnership with his brother Peter, Frantz and his family moved to Texas in 1900. He soon acquired the Standard Bale Wire Buckle Company, which manufactured cotton-bale wire buckles. Frantz also patented a piston ring, a scratcher for oil rigs, and other inventions. During World War II, he served as general superintendent of the American Manufacturing Company.
Source:
Frantz, Ezra Allen. Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed December 7, 2010. http://www.tshaonline.org/handbook/online/articles/ffr06.
Scope and Contents
The Ezra A. Frantz Papers, 1906-1960, consist of the business records of the Frantz Buckle Company in Weatherford, Texas, as well as personal records of Frantz and his social activities. The business records include correspondence, ledgers and journals, printed material, architectural drawings, and advertising materials, while the personal records contain correspondence, lists, newspaper clippings, and other items related to the Church of the Brethren of Texas and Louisiana and Frantz’s rental properties.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research use.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Frantz, Ezra A. -- Archives.; Frantz, Joe Bertram, 1917-.; Frantz family.
Subjects (Organizations)
Frantz Buckle Company (Weatherford, Tex.); Church of the Brethren -- Texas.
Subjects
Manufacturing industries -- Texas.
Places
Weatherford (Tex.)
Related Material
See also Frantz (Joe B.) Papers.
Detailed Description of the Papers
- Inventory:
  - Correspondence, 1919-1941 (Box 3K128)
  - Financial papers, 1908-1944, undated (Box 3K128)
  - Financial records: (Box 3K128)
    - Ledgers, 1906-1907 (Box 3K128)
    - Cash book, 1913-1920 (Box 3K129)
    - Ledgers, 1911-1921, 1930-1937 (Box 3K129)
    - Journal, 1911-1921 (Box 4M525)
    - Ledger, 1911-1921 (Box 4M526)
    - Journal, 1913-1920 (Box 4M527)
    - Ledgers, 1933-1944 (Box 3K130)
    - Journals, 1935-1955 (Box 3K130)
  - Unprocessed papers, 1920-1960 (Box 2.325/A180)
  - Unprocessed papers, 1920-1960 (Box 2.325/U509)